Maxence Dalmais == 40 rue turbil

69003 Lyon – FRANCE

tel: <u>+33.6.78.87.56.20</u> <u>maxence@maxired.fr</u> github.com/maxired

## **Summary**

I'm currently working as a Research and Development software engineer at Worldline. Our team main goal is to support the development of new businesses though new technologies.

Full stack developper, I am a polyglote developper, particulary enthousiat toward Network oriented development.

Linux and OpenSource softwares integration and developement and my daily Job.

## **Experiences**

#### Research and Development Engineer

Worldline, Lyon, France (07/2013 - Present)

- Lead Robotics and connected objects tracks: ROS, OpenCV, hosted services
- Managed and organized Worldline presence at Innorobo 2014 summit
- Participate in developement of new hosting solutions and offer

#### **Development and Innovation Engineer**

Atos Worldline, Lyon, France (10/2010 - 07/2013)

- Full stack JavaScript developer : <u>smartdata.io</u> and <u>beekeper</u>
- iOS and Android project leader and developper : <u>worldline-statistics</u>
- Responsive Web and NoSQL experiences

#### **Network research trainee**

## Commissariat à l'énergie atomique (French National Research Center)

Authentication for Mobile IP Network, Paris, France - Design and Implementation of a global authentication solution for Mobile IP network - Applicative layer access control solution for ad-hoc L2

secured network - Implementation of an IPv6 mobile route advertisement protocol

#### Research network trainee

## DGA (French Government Defense agency), Rennes, France

Establishment and Experimentation on a Mobile ad-hoc Network - Establishment and Experimentation on a Mobile ad-hoc Network composed of mobiles sensors : IP Mobility, GPS, Video Streaming - Performance review of routing protocole OLSR - State of the art of networked robotics

## **Personal Projects**

From my study to now, I worked on lots of network oriented personnal projects. Here are some of them.

#### **DHCP JS**

DHCP JS is an partial implementation of a DHCP server in JavaScript. While working on bare metal provisionning, I needed an extensible DHCP server. As I couldn't find one, I forked one and redesigned it to fit my needs.

#### SNR6

SNR6 is Stateless Naming Resolution protocol over IPv6 designed and Implemented during Network Architecture (CS540) lecture at KAIST. The goal whose to build a zeroconf naming protocol for LAN, in order to increase usages on IPv6 for local network and to reduce number of packets.

#### **IPForge** - Java Packet Forge

JPForge was a Graphical software allowing to forge network packets before sending them on the network. It can be considered as a reversed wireshark, and was usefull for education and testing purpose.

#### **Education**

#### **Telecommunication Engineer at INSA**

## National Institute of Applied Sciences - Grandes $\tilde{A}$ ©coles - Lyon, France ( 2007 - 2010 )

Telecommunication, Network and Software development.

#### **Master Degree student at KAIST**

Exchange semester at Korean Advanced Institut of Science and Technology, Daejon, South Korea (02/2020 - 07-2010)

Advanced network, Distributed System, Game theory , Management for Innovation t

# Telecommunication and Network Technician

2 years technical degree (IUT) in University Joseph Fourrier, Grenoble, France

Software developement, network analysis and configuration

### Languages

• French : Native Language

• English : Professional working proficiency

• German: Limited working proficiency

### **Experiences Outside France**

- Exchange Semester in South Korea
- Summer Internship in Karlshurhe, Germany
- Personals travels to USA, india, australia and across Europa